--------------------------
Movietown News presents
Spotlight on Adventure.
What you are now witnessing
Is footage never before seen by civilized humanity.
A lost world in South America.
Lurking in the shadow of majestic Paradise Falls.
It sports plants and animals undiscovered by science.
Who would dare set foot on this inhospitable summit?
Why, our subject today,
Charles Muntz!
The beloved explorer lands his dirigible, 'The Spirit of Adventure',
In New Hampshire this week,
Completing a yearlong expedition to the lost world.
This lighter-than-air craff was designed by Muntz himself
And is longer than 22 prohibltion paddy wagons placed end to end.
And here comes the adventurer now.
Never apart from his faithful dogs,
Muntz conceived the craft for canine comfort.
It's a veritable floating palace in the sky,
Complete with doggy bath and mechanical canine walker.
And, jiminy Cricket,
Do the locals consider Muntz the bee's knees.
And how! Adventure is out there!
But what has Muntz brought back this time?
Gentlemen, l give you the monsterof Paradise Falls!
But what's this? Scientists cry foul.
The National Explorer'S Society accuses Muntz
Of fabricatlng the skeleton.
No!
The organization strips Muntz of his membership.
Humiliated, Muntz vows a return to Paradise Falls
And promises to capture the beast alive!
I promise to capture the beast alive,
And l will not come back until l do!
And so. The explorer's off to clear his name.
Bon voyage, Charles Muntz,
And good luck capturing the monster of Paradise Falls!
Here's Charles Muntz
Piloting his famous dirigible.
He hurdles Pikes Peak.
He hurdles the Grand Canyon.
He hurdles Mount Everest.
He goes around Mount Everest.
Is there nothing he cannot do?
Yes, as Muntz himSelf says, "Adventure is..."
Adventure s out there! Look out!
Mount Rushmore! Hard to starboard!
Must get Spirit of Adventure over Mount Rushmore!
Hold together, old girl. How're my dogs doing?
All engines ahead full!
Let's take her up to 26,000 feet.
Rudders 18 degrees towards the south.
It's a beautiful day
Winds out of the east at 10 knots.
Visibility unlimited.
Enter the weather in the logbook.
There's something down there. I will bring it back for science.
It's a puppy!
No time! A storm! Lightning hail.
What are you doing?
Don't you know this is an exclusive club?
Only explorers get in here,
Not just any kid
Off the street with a helmet and a pair of goggles.
Do you th nk you've got what it takes? Well, do you?
All right, you're in. Welcome aboard.
What's wrong? Can't you talk?
Hey, I don't bite.
You and me, we're in a club now.
I saw where your balloon went.
Come on! Let's go get it.
My name's Ellie.
There it is.
Well, go ahead.
Go on.
Hey, kid!
Thought you might need a little cheering up.
I got something to show you.
I am about to let you see something
I have never shown to another human being.
Ever! In my life!
You'll have to swear you will not tell anyone.
Cross your heart. Do it!
My Adventure Book.
You know him.
Charles Muntz, explorer.
When I get big, I'm going where he's going,
South Amerca. It's Iike America but south.
Wanna know where I'm gonna live?
"Paradise Falls, a land lost in time."
I ripped this right out of a library book.
I'm gonna move my clubhouse there
And park it right next to the falls.
Who knows what lives up there.
And once I get there...
Well, I'm saving these pages
For all the adventures I'm gonna have.
Only I just don't know how I'm gonna get to Paradise Falls.
That's it! You can take us there in a blimp!
Swear you'll take us. Cross your heart!
Cross it! Cross your heart! Good you promised. No backing out.
Well, see you tomorrow, kid. Bye!
Adventure is out there!
You know, you don't talk very much.
I like you.
Stevie, throw me a deuce!
Quite a sight, huh, Ellie?
Mail is here.
Shady oaks, retirement village. Oh, brother!
Hey, good morning, Mr. Fredricksen.
Need any help there?
No. Yes!
Tell your boss over there
That you boys are ruining our house.
Well, just to let you know,
My boss will be happy to take this whole place off your hand.
And would double his last offer.
What do you say to that?
I'll take that as a no, then.
I believe I made my position to your boss quite clear.
You poured prune juice in his gas tank.
Yeah, that was good!
Here, let me talk to him.
You in the suit. Yes. You.
Take a bath. Hippie!
I am not with him!
This is serious! He's out to get your house!
Tell your boss he can have our house.
I'll take that as a maybe.
Order now. You get the camera,
You get the printer, 4x optical zoom,
Schneider lens, photo printer, SD card.
Good afternoon. My name is Russell.
And I am a wilderness explorer in tribe 54,
Squad lodge 12.
Are you in need of any assistance today, sir?
No.
- I could help you cross the street. - No.
- I could help you cross youryard. - No.
- I could help you cross your porch. - No
Well, I gotta help you cross something.
No, I'm doing fine.
"Good afternoon. My name is Russell."
- Kid... Kid - And I am a Wilderness Explorer
- In Tribe 54 Sweat Lodge 12. -I Slow down. Kid!
- "Are you n need of any assistance..." - Thank you,
- But I don't need any help! -" ...today, sir?"
Proceed.
- "Good afternoon..." -But skip to the end!
See these? These are my Wilderness Explorer badges.
You may notice one is missing.
It's my Assisting the Elderly badge.
If I get it, I'll become a Senior Wilderness Explorer.
The wilderness must be explored!
It's gonna be great! There's a big ceremony,
And all the dads come and they pin on our badges.
So, you want to assist an old person?
Yep! Then I'll be a Senior Wilderness Explorer.
- You ever heard of a snipe? - Snipe?
A bird. Beady eyes.
Every night it sneaks into my yardand
And gobbles my poor azaleas.
I'm elderly and infirm.
I can't catch it.
If only someone could help me.
Me, me, I'll do it!
I don't know, it's awfully crafty.
You'd have to cap your hands three times to lure it in.
I'll find himr, Mr. Fredricksen!
I think its burrow is two blocks down. If you go past...
Two blocks down. Got it. Snipe.
Here, snipey, snipey.
Bring it back here when you find it.
Snipe!
Okay, keep her coming. Keep coming.
And stop. Stop. Stop!
Why.... Hey! Hey, you!
What do you.... What do you think you re doing?
- I am so sorry sir. -Don't touch that
No, no, no. Let me take care of that for you.
- Get away from our mailbox! - Hey Sir, I.
I don't want you to touch it!
Steve, you all right?
It looks bad.
Sorry, Mr. Fredricksen.
You don't seem like a public menace to me.
Take this.
The guys from Shady Oaks will be by to pick you up in the morning, okay?
What do I do now, Ellie?
Good morning, gentlemen.
Good morning, Mr. Fredricksen.
You're ready to go?
Ready as I'll ever be.
Would you do me a favor and take this?
I'll meet you in the van in just a minute.
I wanna say one last goodbye to the old place.
Sure. Take all the time you need, sir.
That's typical. He's probably going to the bathroom for the 80th time.
You think he'd take better care of His house
So long, boys!
I'll send you a postcard from Paradise Falls!
We are on our way, Ellie.
Hi, Mr. Fredricksen.
It's me, Russell.
What are you doing out here, kid?
I found the snipe and I followed it under your porch.
But this snipe had a long tail
And looked more like a large mouse.
Please, let me in.
No.
Oh, alright, you can come....
...in.
I've never been in a floating house before.
Goggles... Look at this stuff!
Wow! You're going on a trip?
"Paradise Falls, a land lost in time".
You're going to South America, Mr. Fredricksen?
Don't touch that! You'll soil it.
You know most people take a plane,
But you're smart,
Because you have your tv, clocks and stuff.
Whoa, is this how you steer your house?
Does it really work?
Kid would you stop with the....
- This makes it go right. - Let go of that...
- And that way's left. - Knock it off
Hey, look! Buildings.
That building's so close, I could almost touch it!
Wow, this is great!
You should try this, Mr. Fredricksen.
Look, there's a bus
That could take me home two blocks away!
Hey, I can see your house from here.
Don't jerk around so much, kid. Whoa!
Well, that's not gonna work.
I know that cloud, it's a cumulonimbus.
Did you know that a cumulonimbus forms
When warm air rises over cool air?
I stayed up all night blowing up ballons... For what?
...and that's how we get lightning.
- That's nice kid - Mr. Fredricksen?
- What are you doing over there? - Look.
See? Cumulonimbus.
My pack!
Got ya!
I thought you were dead.
What happened?
I steered us. I did it! I steered the house.
Steered us?
After you tied your stuff down, you took a nap.
So I went ahead and steered us down here.
Yeah, sure.
I can't tell where we are.
Oh, we're in South Amerca all right.
It was a cinch with my Wilderness Explorer GPS.
- GP What? - My dad gave it to Me.
It shows exacty where we are on the planet.
With this baby, we'll never be lost!
Well get you down, find a bus stop,
You just tell the man you wanna go back to your mother.
Sure, but I don't think they have buses in Paradise Falls.
There. That ought to do it.
Here, I'll give you some change for the bus fare.
No, I'll just use my city bus pass.
That's gonna be Iike a billion on transfers
To get back to my house.
Mr. Fredricksen, how much longer?
Well, we're up pretty high.
Could take hours to get down.
That thing was.... Building or something.
What was that, Mr. Fredricksen?
We can't be cose to the ground yet.
Wait! Wait, no don't! Don't don't!
Wait, wait. Wait!
Russell, hang on.
- Walk back. Walk back. - Okay.
Come on. Come on.
Where.... Where are we?
This doesn't look like the city or the jungle,
Mr. Fredricksen.
Don't worry, Ellie. I got it.
There it is!
Ellie, it's so beautiful!
We made it!
We made it! Russe, we could float right overthere!
Climb up, climb up!
You mean, assist you?
- Yeah, yeah, whatever. - Okay, I'll climb up!
- Watch it! - Sorry.
Now, when you get up there, go ahead and hoist me up.
Got it?
You on the porch yet?
What? That's it?
I came all this way here to get stuck
At the wrong end of this rock pile?
Great.
Hey, if I could assist you over there,
Would you sign off on my badge?
What are you talking about?
We could walk your house to the fall.
- Walk it? - Yeah.
After all, we weigh it down,
We could walk it right overthere.
Like a parade balloon.
Now, we're gonna walk to the falls quickly and quietly
With no rap music or flash dancing.
We have three days at best
Till the helium leaks out of those balloons.
And if we are not at the falls when that happens
-Sand - We're not getting to the falls.
I found sand!
Don't you worry, Ellie.
We'll get our house over there.
It is fun already, isn't it?
By the tme we get there,
You're gonna feel so assisted
Oh, Mr. Fredricksen,
If we happen to get separated,
Use the wilderness explorer call.
Wait, why are we going to paradise falls, again?
Hey, let's play a game.
It's called "see who can be quiet the longest."
Cool! My mom loves that game!
Darn thing!
Come on, Russell. Would you hurry it up?
I'm tired. And my knee hurts.
Which knee?
My elbow hurts and I have to go to the bathroom.
I asked you about that five minutes ago.
Well, I didn't have to go then!
I don't wanna walk anymore.
Can we stop?
Russell, if you don't hurry up,
The tigers will eat you.
There are no tigers in South America. Zoology.
Oh, for the love of Pete!
Go on into the bushes and do your business.
Okay. Here! Hold my stuff.
I've always wanted to try this.
Mr. Fredricksen,
Am I supposed to dig the ho e before or after?
None of my concern!
Oh. It's before!
Tracks?
Snipe.
Here, snipe. Come on out snipe.
Snipe!
Ha, Gotya. Don't be afraid, little snipe.
I am a Wilderness Explorer,
So I'm a friend to all of nature.
Want some more?
Hi, boy. Don't eat it all. Come on out.
Come on. Come on. Don't be afraid, little snipe.
Nice snipe. Good little snipe. Nice....
Giant snipe.
- I found the snipe. - Oh, did you?
- Are they tall? - Oh, yes. They're very tall.
Do they have a Iot of colors?
They do indeed!
- Do they like chocolate? - Oh, yeah
Chocolate?
- Gah! What is that thing? - It's a snipe!
There's no such thing as a snipe!
But you said snipes eat your...
Go on! Get out of here! Go on!
Careful, Russell.
Hey, look, Mr. Fredricksen. It likes Me.
- Russell! - No, stop! That tickles!
Get out of here. Go on! Get!
Uh-oh. No, no no! Kevin! It's okay.
Mr. Fredrcksen is nice.
- Kevin? - Yeah That's his name I just gave him.
Beat it! Vamoose! Scram!
Hey! Thats mine!
Shoo! Shoo Get out of here!
Go on! Beat it!
Can we keep him? Please?
I'll get the food for him. I'll walk him.
I'll change his newspapers
No.
An explorer is a friend to all,
Be it a plant, a fish or a tiny mole.
- That doesn't even rhyme. - Yeah it does.
- Hey, look, Kevin. - What?
Hey, get down! You're not allowed up there!
You come down here right now!
Sheesh!
Can you believe this, Ellie?
Ellie?
Hey, Ellie! Could I keep the bird?
She said for you to let me.
But I told him no. I told you no.
N-O.
I see you back there.
Go on! Get out of here. Shoo! Go annoy someone else for a while.
Hey, are you okay over there?
Hello?
Hello, sir! Thank goodness.
It's nice to know someone else is up here.
I can smell you.
What? You can smell us?
- Hey! - You were talking to a rock.
Hey, that one looks like a turtle.
Look at that one! That one looks like a dog!
- It is a dog. - What?
We're not allowed to have dogs in my apartment.
Hey, I like dogs!
We have your dog!
Wonder who he belongs to.
Sit, boy.
Hey, look, he's trained. Shake.
- Speak. - Hi, there.
Did that dog just say "Hi, there"?
Oh yes.
My name is Dug. I have just met you, and I love you.
My master made me this collar.
He is a good and smart master and he made me this collar
So that I may talk. Squirre!
My master is good and sma.
It's not possible.
Oh, it is, because my master is small.
Cool. What do these do, boy?
Hey, would you
I use that coIIar...
To talk with. I would be happy if you stopped.
Russell, don't touch that.
It could be radioactve or something!
I am a great tracker.
My pack sent me on a specia mission all by myself.
Have you seen a bird?
I want to find one, and I've been on the scent.
I am a great tracker. Did I mention that?
Hey, that is the bird.
I have never seen one up close,
But this is the bird.
May I take your bird up to camp as my prisoner?
Yes, yes, take it.
And on the way, learn how to bark like a real dog.
I can bark.
And here's howling.
Can we keep him? Please, please, please.
- No. - But it's a talking dog!
It's just a weird trick or something.
Let's get to the fall.
Please be my prisoner!
Oh please, oh, please be my prisoner!
Oh! Here it is. I picked up the bird's scent!
Wait a minute, wait a minute! What is this?
Chocolate. I smell chocolate.
I'm getting prunes and ginger cream. Who are they?
Oh, man, the master will not be pleased.
We'd better tell him someone took the bird,
Right, Alfa?
No.
Soon enough the bird will be ours yet again.
Find the scent, my compadres,
And you too shall have much rewardings
From Master for the toil factor you wage.
Alpha, I think there's something wrong with your collar.
You must have broken it.
Yeah. Your voice sounds funny.
Beta! Gamma! Mayhaps you desire to.... Squirrel
Mayhaps you deslre to challenge the ranking
That l have been assigned by my strength and cunning.
No, no, no But Maybe Dug would.
You might wanna ask him.
Yeah. I wonder if he's found the bird
On his very specia mission
Do not mention Dug to me at this time.
His fool's errand will keep him most occupied!
Most occupied indeed.
Do you not agree with that which I am saying to you now?
Sure, but the second Master finds out
You sent Dug out by himself,
None of us will get a treat.
You are wise, my trusted lieutenant.
This is Alpha calling Dug. Come in. Dug.
Hi, Alpha. Hey, your voice sounds funny.
I know, I know! Have you seen the bird?
Why, yes. The bird is my prisoner now.
Yeah, rght!
Impossible. Where are you?
I am here with the bird
And l will bring it back, and then you will like me.
- Gotta go. - Hey, Dug, who you talking to?
- No, wait, wait! - What's Dug doing?
Why is he with the small mailman?
Where are they?
There he is. Come on.!
Oh, please, oh, please, oh, please be my prisoner.
Dug, stop bothering Kevin!
That man there says I can take the bird,
And I love that man there like he is my master.
I am not your master!
I am warning you once again, bird.
- Hey! Quit it - I am jumping on you now bird.
Russell, at this rate we'll never get to the falls.
Here bird.
I am nobody's Master, got it?
I don't want you here, and I don't want you here!
I'm stuck with you!
And if you two don't clear out of here by the time I count to three...
A ball! Oh, boy, oh, boy, a ball!
Ball? Yeah yeah? You want it, boy?
Yes, I do. I do ever so want the ball.
- Go get it! - Oh boy! Oh boy!
I will get it and then bring it back!
Quick, Russell, give me some chocolate.
- Why? - Just give to me!
Bird! Bird!
Come on, Russell.
Wait! Wait, Mr. Fredricksen!
What are we doing?
Hey, we're pretty far now. Kevin's gonna miss me.
I think that did the trick.
Hi, master.
Afternoon.
Well, thanks for keeping us dry, anyway, Ellie.
Which one is the front?
Oh, boy.
Is this step three or step five?
There.
All done. That's for you.
Tents are hard.
Wait. Aren't you super wilderness guy,
With the GPMs and the badges?
Yeah, but can I tell you a secret?
- No. - All right. Here it goes.
I never actually built a tent before. There! I said it.
You've been camping before, haven't you?
Well, never outside.
Well, why didn't you ask your dad how to build a tent?
I don't think he wants to talk about this stuff.
Why don't you try him sometime. Maybe he'll surprise you.
Well, he's away a lot. I don't see him much.
He's gotta be home sometime.
Well, I call, but Phyllis told me I bug him too much.
Phyllis? You call your own mother by her first name?
Phyllis isn't my mom.
But he promised he'd come to my Explorers Ceremony
To pin on my Assisting The Elderly Badge.
So, he can show me about tents then, right?
Hey, why don t you get some sleep?
Don't wanna wake up the traveling flea circus.
Mr. Fredricksen,
Dug says he wants to take Kevin prisoner.
We have to protect him.
Can Kevin go with us?
All right, he can come.
Promise you won't leave him?
- Yeah. - Cross your heart?
Cross my heart.
What have I got myself into, Ellie?
Good morning, sweetheart.
We'd better get moving.
Bird's gone.
Maybe Russell won't notice. All right, everybody up!
Where's Kevin? He's wondered off!
Kevin! Dug, find Kevin!
Find the bird, find the bird! Point!
Look! There he is.
Point!
Hey, that's my food! Get off my roof!
Yeah, get off of his roof!
What is it doing?
The bird is calling to her babies.
Her babies!
Kevin is a girl?
Her house s over there in those twisty rocks.
She has been gathering food for her babies
And must get back to them.
Wait, Kevin is just leaving.
But you promised to protect her.
Her babies need her. We gotta make sure they're together.
Sorry, Russell. We've lost enough time already.
Yeah.
This was her favorite chocolate.
Because you sent her away, there's more for you.
Kevin?
Where's the bird? You said you had the bird!
Oh, yes, oh, yes.
Since I have said that, I can see how you would think that.
- Where is it? - Uh.... Tomorrow.
Come back tomorrow, and then I will again have the bird. Yes.
You lost it. Why do I not have a surprised feeling?
Well, at least you now have led us to the small mailman
And the one who smells of prunes.
The master will be most pleased we have found them.
He will ask them many questions. Come.
Wait! We're not going with you.
We're going to the falls!
Get away from me!
Get down!
Stay!
You came here in that?
Uh, yeah.
In a house? A floating house?
That is the darnest thing I've ever seen!
You're not after my bird, are you?
But if you needed to borrow a cup of sugar
I'd be happy to oblige.
Well, this is all a misunderstanding.
My dogs made a mistake.
Wait. Are you Charles Muntz?
Yeah, well, yes.
The Charles Muntz?
Adventure's out there!
It's really him! That's Chares Muntz!
- It is? Who's Charles Muntz? - Him!
My wife and I, we were your biggest fans.
Oh, well. You're a man of good taste.
Now, you must be tired. Hungry?
Uh-huh.
Now, attention, everyone!
These people are no longer intruders. They are our guests.
Follow me. I Iike you temporarily.
You do smile like prunes.
I will not bite you.
The small mailman smells like chocolate!
I'm sorry about the dogs,
- I hope they weren't too rough on you. - We weren't.
Go ahead and moor your airship right next to mine.
We are not actually going inside the Spirit of Adventure itself?
Would you like to?
Would I?
Wait up, Mr. Muntz!
Jiminy Cricket!
- Not you! - What do we do with Dug?
He lost the bird. Put him in the Cone of Shame.
I do not like the Cone of Shame.
Most of the collection is housed in the world's top museums.
New York, Munich, London.
Of course I kept the best for myself.
Did you ever! WiII you Iook at that?
Oh, yes, the Arsinoitherium.
Beast charged while I was brushing my teeth.
Used my shaving kit to bring it down.
Oh yeah. Well, surprise me.
Only way to get it out of Ethiopia at the time
Was to have it declared as denta equipment.
Oh, my gosh! The giant Somalian Somalian Labradodis!
Oh, you recognize it? I'm impressed!
There's an interesting story there.
Excellent choice.
I found it on safari with Roosevelt.
He and I fell into a habit of
Playing Gin Rummy in the evenings,
And did he cheat!
Oh, he was horrible.
Master, dinner is ready.
Oh, dear, broken translator.
I think it's that loose wire again. There you go, big fellow.
Thank you, Master.
I liked his other voice.
Well, dinner is served. Right this way.
So, how are things States side, huh?
Almost tempted to go back a few times.
But I have unfinished work here.
Please! I hope you're hungry.
Because Epsilon is the finest chef I've ever had.
Oh, Epsilon, you've done it again!
Yes!
Hey! Hey!
Oh. My Ellie would have loved all these.
You know its because of you she had this dream
To come down here and ve by Paradise Falls.
I'm honored. And now you've made it.
You sure we're not bothering you? I'd hate to impose.
No, no, it's a pleasure to have guests.
A real treat.
- Treat? - Where's my treat? I want my treat!
No, no. Quiet! Calm down, calm down.
- I want a treat! I want a treat! - Hey!
I shouldn't have used that word.
Having guests is a delight!
More often I get thieves come to steal what is rightfully mine.
No.
They called me a fraud, those
But once I bring back this creature,
My name will be cleared.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Oh, I've spent a lifetime tracking it.
Sometimes years go by between sightings.
I've tried to smoke it out of that death land where it lives.
You can't go in after it.
Once in, there's no way out.
I lost so many dogs.
And here they come, these bandits,
And think the bird is theirs to take.
But they soon found that this mountain
Is a very dangerous place.
Hey, that looks like Kevin.
- Kevin? - Yeah, that's my new giant pet bird!
I trained it to follow us.
Follow you? It's impossible. How?
- She likes chocolate. - Chocolate?
Yeah. I gave hersome of my chocolate. She goes gaga for it.
But it ran off. It's gone now.
You know Carl, these people who pass through here,
They all tell pretty good stories.
A surveyor making a map.
A botanist cataloguing plants.
An old man taking his house to Paradise Falls.
I mean that's the best one yet.
I cant wait to hear how it ends.
Well, it's been a wonderful evening, but we'd better be going.
Oh, you're not leaving.
We don't want to take advantage of your hospitality.
Come on, Russell.
But we haven't even had dessert yet.
Oh, the boy is right. You haven't had dessert.
Epsilon here makes a delicious cherries jubilee.
Oh. You really must stay! I insist!
We have so much more to talk about!
Kevin?
It's here.
Get them!
- Hurry! - I am hurrying!
Ahhh! They're coming!
Master! Over here!
Go toward the light, Master!
Russell!
Get back!
Go on, master! I will stop the dogs!
Stop, you dogs!
Help!
Give me your hand!
Hang on to Kevin!
Kevin.
No, no, no. Kevin. Stay down.
She's hurt real bad. Can't we help her get home?
All right, but we gotta hurry.
You lost them?
No, it was Dug.
Yeah. He's with them. He helped them escape!
Wait.
Wait a minute. Dug.
See anything?
No, my pack is not following us. Boy, they are dumb.
This is crazy.
I finally meet my chidlhood hero,
And he's trying to kill us. What a joke!
Hey, I know a joke.
A squirrel walks up to a tree and says,
"I forgot to store acorns for winter and now I am dead".
Ha! It s funny because the squirrel gets dead.
Careful, Russell.
You okay, Kevin?
You know what, Mr. Fredricksen?
The wilderness isn't quite what I expected.
Yeah? How so?
It's kind of wild.
I mean, it's not how they made it sound in my book.
Get used to that, kid.
My dad made it sound so easy.
He is really good at camping,
And how to make fire from rocks and stuff
He used to come to all my squad lodge meetings.
And afterwards, we go get icecream that fattens.
I always get chocolate and he gets butter brickle.
Then we sit on this one curb, right outside
And I'll count all the blue cars and he counts all the red ones,
And whoever gets the most wins.
I like that curve.
It might sound boring,
But I think the boring stuff is the stuff I remember the most.
Look, there it is!
Hold on, Russell, stand still.
Look at that bird go! Wait up, you overgrown chicken!
That's it! Go, Kevin!
Go find your babies!
Run, Kevin, run!
Oh, no!
Russell, give me your knife!
Get away from my bird!
No!
Careful, I want it in good shape for my return.
Let her go! Stop!
Kevin!
You gave away Kevin.
You just gave her away.
This is none of my concern.
I didn't ask for any of these!
Master, it's all right.
I am not your master!
If you hadn't have shown up, none of these would have happened.
Bad dog! Bad dog!
Now, whether you assist me or not,
I am going to paradise falls, if it kills me!
Here. I don't want this anymore.
Russell?
Russell!
I'm gonna help Kevin, even if you won't!
No, Russell, no!
Russell?
Dug!
I was hiding under your porch because I love you.
Can I stay?
Can you stay? Well, you're my dog, aren't you?
And I'm your master.
You're my master?
Oh boy! Oh boy!
Good boy, Dug! You're a good boy!
Yes!
Don't worry, Kevin, I'll save...
And they wouldn't believe me.
Just wait till they get a look at you!
Master.
- The small mailman has returned. - What?
Let me go!
Where is your elderly friend?
He's not my friend anymore.
Well, if you're here, Fredricksen can't be far behind.
Where are you keeping Kevin?
Let me go!
Scream all you want, small mailman.
None of your mailmen friends can hear you.
I will unleash all my wilderness explorer training!
Alfa, Fredricksen is coming back!
Guard that bird.
If you see the old man, you know what to do
Hey, where are you going? I'm not finished with you!
Nice talking with you.
Where are you, Fredricksen?
Help!
Russell!
- Mr. Fredricksen! - Dug, bring that over!
You came back for Kevin! Let's go get her!
I'm getting Kevin. You stay here.
But I wanna help.
I don't want your help.
I want you safe.
How do we get pass these dogs?
Point!
Kevin!
Don't worry, Kevin. We are on our way.
Allow no one should be enterring through these doors.
Guard well that bird, my minions.
What do we do now, Dug?
Who wants the ball?
- Me. I want it! - Me. I do!
- I want the ball! - Give it to me!
Then go get it!
I'm gonna get there first!
Getting the ball!
I got it!
Uh-oh.
I'm sorry, Kevin. Let's get you out of here.
- Master! He's gone! The old man! - What's going on?
- He's here! - He's got the bird! - The bird's gone...
Calm down! One at a time!
I want...to...help!
- He's in Hall D! - He's in Hall C!
It's the old man!
Does anyone know where they are?
Gray Leader? Take down the house.
Gray Leader checking in.
Gray Two, checking in.
Gray Three, checking in.
Target sighted.
Come on, Kevin.
Hi.
Any Iast words, Fredricksen?
Come on! Spit it out!
- Come on. - Enough
I am taking that bird back with me. Alive or dead.
Come on, Kevin.
I will have many enjoyments from what I am about to do, Dug.
He wears the Cone of Shame!
What? Do not just continue sitting. Attack!
No, no! Stop your laughing!
Get this off of me!
Listen, you dog. Sit!
Yes, Alpha.
Alpha? I am not Alpha. He is....
Oh!
I can't do it.
Russell.
You leave Mr. Fredricksen alone!
Hey! Squirrel!
SquirreI? Where? Where? Where?
Where's the squirrel?
I hate squirrels!
Dug!
Master!
Russell, over here! Let's go!
Mr. Fredricksen!
Go on, Kevin.
No!
Russell, get out of there!
No. Leave them alone!
Russell, hang on to kevin! Don't let go of her.
Kevin! Chocolate!
That was cool!
Don't jerk around so much, kid. Easy Russell.
Oh, I am ready to not be up high.
Sorry about your house, Mr. Fredricksen.
You know, its just a house.
Look at you. You're so soft.
I wish I could keep one.
Where is my cane? I just had it here.
You know what? Keep them. A little gift from me to you.
Bye Kevin!
Ready?
Ready.
And by receiving their badges,
The following Explorers will graduate to Senior Explorers.
For Extreme Mountaineering Lore. Congratulations. Jimmy.
For Wild Animal Defensive Arts. Congratulations. Brandon.
For Assistlng the Elderly....
Uh, Russe , is there someone that....
Excuse me. Pardon me. Old man coming through.
I'm here for him.
Congratulations, Russell. Sir.
Russell, for Assisting the Elderly
And for performing above and beyond the call of duty,
I would like to award you the highest honor I can bestow.
The Ellie Badge.
All right. I think that covers everybody.
So let's give a big explorer call
To our brand new Senior Wilderness Explorers.
Ready, everybody?
- Blue one. - Red one
- Blue one. - Gray one.
- Red one. - That's a bike.
It's red, isn't it?
Mr. Fredricksen, you're cheating.
No, I'm not. Red one.
That's a fire hydrant.
Maybe I need new lessons.
Another blue one.